这是我全新的火箭发射4K直播车
Today, we're going to be building this thing out to be the ultimate 4k live streaming mobile studio that we can take to any of the launch sites here in the United States.
Because as you guys know, there's a lot of really exciting launches coming up here in the next little bit of time.
So many new rockets and exciting things coming up that we want to be there and producing the best footage we can.
So join us for this little different video for this channel as we build out a 4k mobile studio.
Allow me to introduce myself, if you are new to the channel here, my name is Tim Dodd.
I teach rocket stuff on YouTube,
I go out and I interview experts about all sorts of aerospace things,
and I try to go to some rocket launches occasionally in person, and then live stream them as best I can.
And that's especially true when it's something new and exciting, such as a brand new rocket that's never flown before,
or maybe an exciting mission with humans on board or something like that.
And I've done this all over the place at NASA's Kennedy Space Center in Florida
or at SpaceX's Starbase facility where they're working on their massive Starship prototype rocket.
It's been super fun and hopefully I can do this anywhere now.
But I'm not gonna lie, I've had some pretty terrible luck with live streams.
Hi, it's me, Tim Dodd, the Everyday Astronaut. Uh, I hope you guys can hear me. I hope you can see me....
Uh, here we go guys... [static]. I love it.
It wouldn't be Everyday Astronaut live stream if there wasn't something ridiculous happening.
What is that? Big pieces of something?
There are pieces falling.
I think it blew up. I think they just did. I think they did flight termination.
We're gonna have a boom here guys get ready.
Oh, they blew it outta the sky.
We may have just lost about 20 grand worth of gear.
There's some things that I'm proud of in life and this is not one of them.
Sorry, Andrew this is my live streams - [extreme laughter] Oh God.
So that's why I bought this, a 2011 Ford E-350. That was previously a production truck for NBC.
Now here's the deal, I wanted to be able to take all of our expensive production gear
that was previously basically just sitting in a closet at our studio space in Texas
and I wanna be able to get it on the road.
Especially after our last livestream fiasco at the SLS rollout, I wanted to make sure that never happened again.
So I'm gonna give you guys a tour of how the van was at the very beginning when we first bought it,
how we kind of fixed it up and worked on it and tried out things like the mast for the first time and lots of other fun little things.
And then lastly, I'll give you a tour of the entire vehicle when it's done, as we prepare to go on the road for the very first time.
Welcome! <Laugh>.
Okay. So check this thing out. Uh, right now it's kind of a little bit in, uh, an in between mode of where we're gonna be.
We're gonna be stripping this thing out for the most part,
putting in a different desk here and that will have all the monitors,
the panel for switching,
and then this whole rack here will be will be set up with all of our encoding gear and our switcher and
the things that allow us to paint and let the cameras in our, in our audio switcher, everything's gonna live in that rack,
but I think we're actually gonna remove this rack here,
'cause we have plenty of rack space for what we're gonna be doing. Um,
and this will free us up to be able to hopefully put two people side by side at this desk and have a work station.
So someone can be on a computer and the other person can be running the show.
So we can actually have two people operating a show live and hopefully it works out pretty good for that. I think it, I think it will.
So we're actually swapping this entire panel out.
We're gonna get a new custom made panel for our needs and it's gonna have like how many SDIs? A lot.
It's like 24 SDIs or something or like at least 20 in and like 10 out or something.
And then HDMIs in and out. Still have the power outlets, all that stuff.
We should have a pretty good mobile solution here.
And then we'll be able to plug cameras into the outside here and run a whole show mobile. Hopefully, that'll be able to make it so, you know, as nice and reliable.
Okay. So, uh, around back here, this is, to me, this is actually kind of where this gets fun because, uh, well, we're,
we're buying some stuff at the moment, like a, a new, uh, you know,
little gen or not a generator, a new air compressor,
a vacuum and things like that. But you'll notice there's a giant pole running up and down the middle of this thing. That my friends is a 70 foot tall pole.
So basically like 20 some meters tall, really hilariously tall pole.
You hook a... We're gonna hook up the air compressor to it and we're gonna test it out here, see if it actually works,
but it can go up and we're gonna actually eventually be mounting a camera that can be nice and stable
which will basically give us, you know, what it'll feel like drone views because it'll be 70 feet up in the air it'll feel a lot like a drone,
but of course at places like Kennedy Space Center, Vanderberg Air Force Base, you can't fly a drone.
So this will be a, a unique vantage point that you really wouldn't be able to get anywhere else.
So we're really excited about that. We're really excited to test it out
and the cool thing too, for us with so much gear, this is basically just where a lot of the gear is gonna live
you know when we're traveling on the road and stuff, we'll be able to store, you know, tripods and things like that and it should be pretty awesome.
What are you working on?
Taking apart all of our hard work that we've spent on the last year building this... All going away.
So some of the cables are starting to come a little bit unfraid weren't they? Yeah.
Like kind of pulled onto tight.
Yeah. We had a really tight space up in there for all of our old SDI connections. The Constellation 8K has like insane amount of inputs,
so it's really tight.
And then we had it in this fly case in case we were gonna take it on the road,
but now taking on the road means putting it in there instead.
Welcome to the world of racking and unracking things. Oh yeah.
Talk about SDI.
Yeah. Look at that old school analog baby. Well,
I don't about analog. Not anymore. Not anymore.
So are you excited for this part? Yeah.
You actually are. Aren't you <laugh> like plugging in all, every one of those things basically will have an SDI and/or
network cables coming into every single one. A few XLRs... Not a ton of XLR, actually.
Not a lot. Yeah. It's mostly Dante. Which is nice.
Here's carnage from our, uh, the old one previous. Some, some we might be able to reuse.
Yeah. We can reuse a bunch of these probably.
Yep. We made all of these, every single one of these, you see, we made for our last rack and used literally what, like three times <laugh> ugh. Alright,
this baby needs to go in there.
And be sure don't shoot the license plate.
I just realize we haven't taken that off again because as you know, privacy's a really big deal,
which is why I'm really excited about having incogni as a sponsor of today's video.
As I'm sure, you know, your personal data is being tracked, sold, and exploited every single day with identity theft and spam phone calls and
emails at an all time high,
it's really important to take control of your personal data because here's the deal.
Websites actually sell your personal data to thousands of brokers and not only is that just pretty weird,
it's actually a pretty big security risk and can lead to things like identity theft or hacks.
And personally, I think it's even stranger that literally anyone can just buy your personal information, like your date of birth, your phone number, your email, your address, your social security number,
or even things like your shopping habits, which just feels really weird to me.
I mean, if someone looked at my shopping habits right now, they'd be like, "Why does this guy love cables so much?
He spent thousands of dollars on cables recently."
Now you actually have the right to request to have all your information removed from all these different brokers,
but the problem is doing that manually would literally take years.
And here's where incogni comes in.
They do all the work for you to reach out on your behalf to all of these countless data brokers,
to ensure that your personal information is scrubbed from the internet.
All you have to do is sign up, give incogni the right to work for you,
and then you just sit back and let them take care of the rest.
The first 100 people to use code "astronaut" at the link below will get 20% off of incogn, or you can can just visit incogni.com/astronaut to learn more.
Thank you so much incogni for sponsoring today's video.
Alright, welcome to the inaugural raising of the pole, the pole erection.
So this is our first time ever raising the pole, so we have no idea if the mast works or anything, we've got a compressor ready.
We've got a battery, 'cause currently, we don't have all of the generator stuff ready to go.
So this is our only decent way to test this.
And we're gonna go ahead and tie some ropes to it because here's the deal that mass is supposed to have like at least 50 pounds in order to really be able to come back down in a timely manner.
And right now there's basically nothing on top of it at all
power, go, go compressor, pneumatic, where go on pneumatic.
Now we're gonna go ahead and build up pressure. That's actually really quiet.
It said it's quiet. That's hilariously quiet.
Here we go 3, 2, 1. Oh, it is already going!
Look at that! We have lift off.
Yes! I'm so happy 'cause I don't know. How would you fix one of these?
You know, if you had an issue, like where do you go to be like, I need my weird 70 foot tall mast fixed.
That's a- oh no! It's peeing. Why is it peeing over everything over the-. Oh God! Inverter.
Got something to put it in? I don't know, just grab it. Oh God. Um.
Someone grab something! That's ancient rainwater. <laugh>.
Here move the inverter. Oh God teaming with life. Yes. How bad is inverter soaked? Not bad.
Okay, good. Oh my gosh. Why!? Now
it's coming out the top. Oh, so maybe it's at like the end of each- Yeah.
Segment there. That might not be the worst thing in the world.
Okay. Never seen the end of our... Maybe keep an eye on it... Now we got the top one going.
That's, that's so crazy, dude. That is so high.
That's so much higher than I thought.
Holy crap there's a whole other section.
It's peeing on us from way there.
Why must you do this?
That's pretty great though isn't it like... That's, that's really cool. And it's so tall. That's really tall.
That's like twice or three times as tall as like most of the houses around here.
The crazy thing is you'd be able to get out over, you know, from this vantage point, you could get out over any of the buildings in the area here.
I mean you could get, you could, it's probably almost,
almost like lighthouse deck level there where the, where the people would stand for the lighthouse. That's up there.
Success.
So here we are. Uh, we have made 16-. That's not bad. -SDI cables so far. And we only have. 1,066 To go.
A lot, a lot to go. Uh,
so this is what we're doing is using Belden 48, 55 SDI just rated for 12G,
which means we can do 4k. 4K 60. 4K 60 even.
yeah. Like glove, baby. So let's see...
we want this probably to be as far to the right as we can, right?
Yeah. You kind of want two of them.
Yeah. Like that. That's good. Yeah.
Bad news. Like where the HDMI port is on this thing right behind the bracket, like exactly behind that's a DVI port here and HDMI there.
So in other words, I guess it's saw, saw time.
God. Remember that saw, saw, yeah, baby, those. Problem solved. Problem solved.
Oh baby. So these, these huge chunkers, these are the ecoflows. Uh, these are, these are the Delta pros, uh,
which is 33.6 kilowatt hours of electricity.
Um, absolutely bonkers for what we're doing. So each one of these, so that's 7.2 kilowatt hours. That's 7,200 watt hours of, of juice.
And that's gonna save our butt potentially in the field. Um,
we could run our studio here and the air conditioning, which is very important at most launch sites. Uh, we'll be able to run it for several hours.
Um, and the cool thing is we can, we can actually wire these two together. So I'll just plug this cable in here and this going,
and then we'll power up. Look at that. They're already, they sync together even right away.
Our friends over at ecoflow ended up hooking us up with these batteries. We actually have two here and we're putting two inside the studio.
That way we can keep running the show no matter what. Uninterrupted. Including running air conditioning
and all the other things, lights and everything that we need to run to keep a show going here or on the road.
These things are awesome. A lot of van life people are using these things for a good reason, 'cause it's an insane amount of power they charge in like two hours.
They are incredible units. We're extremely thankful.
So thank you ecoflow for helping us out and helping us make sure that the show goes on no matter what, 'cause that's, that's huge. So yeah, check 'em out.
So we're making a lot of really good progress now.
We officially can take in multiple 4k remote feeds. Um,
they can be miles and miles and miles away actually.
But what I'm really excited about is we now have our new tracking asset up and it is unbelievable. I can't even begin to describe.
Like we have three... We don't have three of these controllers,
but we have three of these heads and the heads are ridiculously expensive,
but look at how smooth- look at this.
I can't even begin to tell you how good this looks from our end here and how good it feels driving.
I mean, we are, we're eight kilometers away.
We're over eight kilometers away and I can control this thing literally like going up and down the tower as if we're 200 meters away. I mean, it's just unbelievably smooth.
Here's the launch mount,
we can swing over quick
and this isn't even and fast. Like we have it set like really down because we don't want it to be too fast. Here's the build site
so we can actually slew it around that quickly and that slowly that's the key is being able to go
fast and slow is the really hard part with these mounts with any kind of tracking unit.
So to be able to do both fast and slow is absolutely unbelievable.
Well check this out. This one has Cooper's uh, Cooper, which, which, uh, scope is that?
It's a C8 from like the 1980s. Um, Celestron? Celestron. Eight inch Schmidt-Cassegrain.
Yep. And we've got it up here on our Ross VR 600 head.
These things can handle like 130 pounds, like 65 kilograms or so...
Butter smooth. Butter smooth.
Yeah. It's so much better than some of the, some of the stuff in the past.
Yeah. I mean, this is like a smooth of, I don't, I mean,
we'll see how we do when push comes to shove when it actually, when it's time,
but in theory, this is so far been really, really impressive.
咱们还有一天就要出发了 今天先带大家尽量了解一下我攒的这辆车吧
之后可能还会有额外升级 毕竟三千预算进卡吧 加钱加到______
Locational Uplinking Networking Asset
欢迎来到LUNA
我们先从机柜最上面说起吧 最上面就是一些网络设备
它下面是网络设备的一些附属设备 没啥好说的
百灵达X32 32路机架式数字调音台 1699$
再往下是调音台 这台是Behringer X32 RACK
有很多XLR接口 但我们更多用的是Dante协议
Dante协议可以让数字音频信号在IP网络上传输
然后这个是视频切换台
11245$
型号Black Magic Constellation 8K 有40个12G-SDI的输入
我最开始还以为这接口数量严重过剩了
当时跟Black Magic的人接洽 帮我选设备 他们帮了挺大的忙
还和助手Andrew等人交流 当时我感觉40路信号实在太多了
肯定用不到那么多 以前最多也只用到8个左右
之后撑死可能再多两路输入吧
结果现在这切换台上75%的接口都用完了 比我最开始想象中多得多
而这机子都能应对自如 太强大了
这款切换台还能支持8K 不过我们现在只用4K模式 走的12G-SDI信号
这点很好 因为我们现在很多设备都用的12G信号 能跑4K@60
再下面 看上去像是风扇 但实际上它后面是三个4K解码器
D300 4K HDMI HEVC Hardware Decoder 699$ x3
Kilo View的4K HDMI解码器
2790$ x2
再下面是Teradek Prism Flex 4K编码器 一共有两台 作为最终的编码器
切换台的PGM信号出来怼到编码器的SDI接口上
它再把编码后的信号推流到内网或者互联网上
直接推流到互联网平台 我们是推到YouTube
1055$
它旁边的是Black Magic UltraStudio 4k Mini
用来提供画面包装
把包装信号 通过SDI进切换台
抠出来放到视频画面上 就出现了平常看到的倒计时钟等其他信息
而它是通过一台装有CasparCG的Nook PC驱动的 它的服务端就在这
Intel Nook机就是个独立的电脑 屏幕在这边 额外的无线键盘还没装
技术导演会坐在这里监看跑CasparCG的Nook PC
坐这里一通操作就行了
总之技术导演坐这里 把握整场节目
而且最好手边能有一台电脑 这样可以实时了解Discord Twitter上的情报
从而获取外部最新的动向 而有些内容在内话里是获取不到的
所以技术导演最好能有一台电脑 然后他旁边还有个人 这车正常运行是两人
另一人会在这里用这台机器操作回放内容
我们叫它"Gamer Station" 因为它就是一台游戏PC
我们需要一台有足够多PCIe通道的电脑
995$
还要有足够空间放下 上面插着BlackMagic的DeckLink 上面有4路SDI的输入输出
这样就能实时捕捉回放画面 在直播的时候就能回放出来
甚至还能做酷炫的慢动作画面
可以取几个镜头 把60帧慢放一半 在直播中回放出来
对于火箭发射来说这种慢放镜头会非常非常酷炫
这就是这台Gamer PC 另外这台电脑还会运行CasparCG
所以程序都是跑在这台电脑上的 它的服务端在之前的Nook上
而这台电脑会跑CasparCG的客户端
操作的两人都能用这个内话通信
这样技术导演就能和各个主持人 甚至各个机位进行通话
整个转播车内部就介绍差不多了
接下来带你们看看外部接口板 信号都从那边进来
就是这里 你们可能看过 外面有个小锁
这些接口板的线能让我们轻松做一场节目
而我们这里除了SDI输入 还有输出
输出还是很重要的 在现场我们可能需要一路监看画面的返送 给摄像跟踪操作手
或者一路节目画面的反送 给主持人之类的
所以需要有这些输出接口
当然现场的摄像机还需要这些输入接口
我们还有几个HDMI 但目前还没使用场景 谁知道呢
目前计划还用不上这些HDMI输入
所以这些接口先放这
还有一些网络接口 都是用于内网的 虽然还不清楚之后会用在什么地方
然后还有几个交流电源插座
我其实希望插座能上到10个左右 我总感觉俩插座功率不太够用
希望不会吧 倒也不会跑太多大功率东西 只是接一些延长线和插线板之类
当然 还有XLR的输入 需要时还能输出 当然绝大多数音频都是跑的Dante协议
所以绝大多数接口可能根本用不上
但有时图方便随手插个麦克风上去也挺好 不用想太多东西
所以有些设备会走XLR接口 但还可以选择Dante协议的音频
差不多介绍完了
我们还要接着收拾设备 本视频第一部分就是这样 介绍这辆车怎么攒出来的
流水账介绍车上各种东西
而明天我们就要出发 真正使用这辆车了
那就是本视频的第二部分了 比如一路的旅程 在现场架机 各种幕后画面
祝我们好运吧 为了给大家提供最高品质的直播我都快被榨干了
这一幕我已经想了好多好多好多年了
最早我还在Twitch上直播的时候就梦想过今天这一刻
2016年就考虑过弄一辆转播车直播火箭发射
我真的很努力想造一个航天飞机外形的拖车
在里面装好一切直播的设备做直播
这一步走了很久 梦想终于成真了
说实话 能在YouTube干这么久 很大原因也是想造这个出来
然后带大家去看各种各样的 我能有幸参加到的火箭发射
后面是感谢与恰饭环节
I couldn't be doing all this stuff without my friends Cosmic Perspective
and Andrew and all those who helped like Ben Stineman, who did a lot of the the decoders and all the stuff. A lot of the wiring.
Andrew spent a lot of time on just tons of stuff. Ryan spent a ton of time filming and helping out with just all sorts of odds and ends,
you know, it's just countless amounts of hours and Cooper helped a lot.
Nic Ansuini. We had Colin out here.
Ryan's or Andrew's friend Ryan or Colin as well.
Just tons of people have been hands on here.
And this was all possible because of the support of all of our viewers here.
So obviously if you guys weren't watching this, we wouldn't be doing something like this,
something that's obscene and crazy to be able to bring it to you guys.
So that's thanks to course our Patreon supporters and our YouTube members. You guys make this all possible.
You know, as you know, there's not been a lot of content coming out lately because we've just been like all hands on with this right now, you know,
there's not been time to do anything else besides getting this van ready to go.
These are huge milestone launches that I don't wanna miss and Patreon has made it so we can just keep reinvesting every single penny,
even though YouTube's like, I have not streamed or I've been able time to do anything on YouTube.
There's no revenue on YouTube right now for me, Patreon is making this happen.
So if you guys do want to help make this possible, uh, head on over to patreon.com/everydayastronaut.
You'll also get some behind the scenes photos and some stuff kind of setting up and things like that. We just occasionally post some stuff there,
but also exclusive live streams as well.
So if you wanna help me do crazy things like this and just gain access to some other fun things, head on over to patreon.com/everydayastronaut.
And of course, while you're online, be sure and head on over to everydayastronaut.com/shop for some awesome merchandise,
such as our awesome new dress shirts, which are super, super cool. We have four different patterns. They're awesome.
We have tons of other really cool nerdy merch, like our schematics.
And then we also have a handful of things that we're preparing for the Artemis stream as well.
So like the RS-25 shirts and stuff like that too.
So head on over to everydayastronaut.com/shop, shop around, and that helps support the channel as well.
Okay. Thank you everybody. That's gonna do it for me. I'm exhausted. We gotta keep packing here and get ready for the road tomorrow.
That's gonna do it for me. I'm Tim Dodd, the Everyday Astronaut bringing space down to earth for everyday people.